Juan Manuel Rivera López Cel. (+57) 301 503 2280

jm.rivera@uniandes.edu.co linkedin.com/in/juanma-rivera/

Double career student of Psychology and Systems and Computer Engineer at Los Andes University, Colombia.

Experienced in developing low-cost equipment to measure learning and acoustic startle in rats and applying CBT techniques to HIV patients in order to improve adherence to treatment.

Interested in developing equipment and technology for investigation and learning techniques to analyze neural data from functional neuroimaging.

Proficient in Python, Java and Arduino.

Academic training

Psychology. Los Andes University. Bogotá, Colombia. 2015, in progress.

Relevant courses: Neurochemistry and psychopharmacology, neuropsychology, investigation design and analysis.

Systems and Computer Engineer. Los Andes University. Bogotá, Colombia. 2015, **in progress.**

Relevant courses: Transactional systems, data structures, object oriented programming

Bioinformatics minor. Los Andes University. Bogotá, Colombia. 2015, in progress.

Relevant courses: Genomic and bioinformatic, biomolecule simulation

NMA - Computational Neuroscience

Neuromatch Academy. July 2021.

Psychological first aid

ASCOFAPSI. Bogotá, December 2020

Introduction to UML

Los Andes University in Coursera. July 2020

Electrons in action: Electronics and Arduino for your own inventions

Pontifical Catholic University of Chile in Coursera. July 2020.

Introduction to Python programming I: Learning to program with Python

Pontifical Catholic University of Chile in Coursera. December 2019.

Work experience

Los Andes University Neuroscience and behaviour laboratory

Research intern (Jun

(June 2019 - December 2019)

Building of a low-cost nosepoke system and a low-cost acoustic startle response system for rodents.

Los Andes University

Principles of Neuroscience Teacher Assistant

(August 2017 - Current)

Organize and teach review lessons previous to exams. Experience related to neuroanatomy, neurochemistry and neurochemistry.

Infectoclínicos de Colombia S.A.S.

Psychology intern

(January 2020 - June 2020)

Applying CBT techniques to HIV patients to improve the adherence to treatment and diagnosis acceptance.

Programs and skills

Programming languages

- Java (Advanced)
- Python (Intermediate)
- SQL (Basic)

Other programs and skills

- SPSS
- E-Prime
- PsychoPy 3
- OfficeSuite
- EAGLE (Basic)

References

Luis Fernando Cardenas, PhD

Associated professor at Los Andes University.

Director of the Neuroscience and Behavior Laboratory.

lucarden@uniandes.edu.co

Sandra Jimena Baez, PhD Associated professor at Los Andes University

sj.baez@uniandes.edu.co